[{"question":"Multivibrators belong to a family of oscillators commonly called","answers":{"a":"Relaxation oscillators","b":"Dynamic oscillators","c":"Stretched oscillators","d":"Static oscillators"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"A bistable multivibrator is a","answers":{"a":"Free running oscillator","b":"Triggered oscillator","c":"Sawtooth wave generator","d":"Crystal oscillator"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"The other name of bistable multivibrator is","answers":{"a":"Flip-Flop","b":"Decoder","c":"Multiplexer","d":"Bidirectional circuit"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"When bistable multivibrator has sine wave as an input, then it is known as","answers":{"a":"Free running multivibrato","b":"Eccles-Jordan circuit","c":"Trigger circuit","d":"Schmitt trigger"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"Bistable multivibrator circuit can be used as","answers":{"a":"Memory element","b":"Pulse stretcher","c":"Clock","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"One shot multivibrator is the other name of","answers":{"a":"Monostable multivibrator","b":"Bistable multivibrator","c":"Astable multbibrator","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"What is the difference between a retriggerable one shot multivibrator and a non-retriggerable one shot multivibrator","answers":{"a":"The non-retriggerable one shot mulivibrator can only be triggered once","b":"The retriggerable one shot mulivibrator can be triggered many times","c":"The output pulse can be stretched with a non-retriggerable one shot mulivibrator.","d":"The output pulse can be stretched with a retriggerable one shot mulivibrator."},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"The function of discharge transistor in the 555-timer circuit is to","answers":{"a":"Charges the timing capacitor when the output is switched to high","b":"Discharges the timing capacitor when the output is switched to low","c":"Discharges the timing capacitor when the output is switched to high","d":"Charges the timing capacitor when the output is switched to low"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"The CMOS version of the 555 timer IC is","answers":{"a":"IC 7486","b":"IC 74138","c":"IC 7555","d":"Option B and C"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"The classic multivibrator circuit is known as ____________","answers":{"a":"Metal-coupled multivibrator","b":"Plate-coupled multivibrator","c":"Parallel-plate coupled multivibrator","d":"Alternate-plate coupled multivibrator"},"correctAnswer":"b"}]
  